JENNIS M. VICENTE-FELICIANO

San Tan Valley, AZ 85140

CONTACT

Phone: (480) 382-2863

Email: jennis.m.vicente@gmail.com

Professional Social Media:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jennisvicente/ Software Development and publications

https://github.com/jennisvicente

EDUCATION

2021 INTERNATIONAL INSTITUTE OF **INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY**

Bangalore, India

Executive PGP in Machine Learning & Al

Python, Advanced SQL, Data Analysis in Excel, Statistics and Exploratory Data Analysis, Machine Learning (I,II), Natural Language Processing, Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning

UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA

Phoenix, AZ

Data Analytics Certificate

Excel VBA, Python, SQL, MongoDB, HTML, Java, Matplotlib, Leaflet, Flask, Heroku apps

COLUMBIA COLLEGE

Columbia, MO

Business Management Coursework

Principles of Management, Organizational Management, Human Resources Management, Business Law I, Business Law II

UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI

Columbia, MO

Mechanical and Nuclear Engineering Coursework

Coursework in Mechanical and Nuclear Engineering. Research in Nuclear Engineering including publications.

UNIVERSIDAD POLITÉCNICA DE PUERTO **RICO**

San Juan, PR

Mechanical Engineering Coursework

FSAE Competition. Secretary in the Student **Board**

SKILLS

- Bilingual (English/Spanish)
- Produce a tangible, positive impact
- Focus on results
- Display strong analytical qualities
- Maintain effective cost control
- Displays excellent intuitive judgement
- Strive for the achievement of excellence
- Polished and confident speaker

PROFILE SUMMARY

Fully bilingual Business Intelligence Engineer and former manager, researcher, and writer whose experience makes the perfect combination to take on any challenge as a Solution Architect. Using technical skills to make an impact on a company or the world. Passionate about learning and innovating; acquiring skills while collaborating with a like-minded team to reach results.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AMAZON, Tempe, AZBusiness Intelligence Engineer, Global Procurement Organization
November 2021 - Present

Apply analytic and business skill to extract insights from datasets Engage business stakeholders in dialogues to convert business problems into logic problems resolved using data, statistics, and/or scripting. Partner with fellow tech teams to implement scalable, automated infrastructure for data extraction, processing, computation, and delivery. Work closely with data engineering and product management to deliver features to customers.

customers.

Identifying new opportunities to influence business strategy and product vision

using data. Accomplishments:

Developed a tool to standardize ordering targets for non-corrugate items that resulted in 10.8% average inventory reduction in 2023 and incremental 3.74% reduction YTD. May YTD outbound volume was 8.3% higher YoY while inventory was \$9.8M less in 2024.

Developed a tool that tracks forecast accuracy of 739 unique packaging items accross 554 sites globally, used in negotiations with suppliers for rebates related to improvements on forecast accuracy.

KELLYOCG, Phoenix, AZ

Manufacturing Tech/ Shift 1 Lead June 2020 - August 2021

SALT/ASH Project Lead August-September 2020

Work in a clean room environment abiding and enforcing safety rules and regulations.

Extensive knowledge of fully automated manufacturing processes. Assess, plan, organize and lead a team to manually continue production while automation is interrupted.

Plan training and certification for new hires as well as monthly audits. Report any safety concerns using the appropriate channels if they can't be immediatély resólved

Ensure our tools are in working order or sent to repair.

DATA SCIENCE CONSULTANTS, LLC, Mesa, AZ

Chief Executive Officer, Founder November 2019 - Present

Data analysis and Data Visualizations: https://www.eq-tracker.xyz/,

https://www.grabandgoAZ.info . Data Consultant, Assistant Project Manager, Data Visualizations and centralization of embedded resources from other websites: https://www.3CoPR.com

WALMART, Maricopa, AZ

Assistant Manager November 2007 - August 2019

- Promote adaptability to company guidelines to increase profit by 10% Increase profitability by creating a "Can it be sold" mentality.

 Make deposits and document cash shortages.
 Coach and train store associates.
 Resolve customers' issues efficiently.

 Work at the cash registers when needed to decrease the waiting time of the customers. Meet sales and growth goals set by the management.

 Deal with loss prevention to lessen shrink.

Accomplishments:

- Top Sales Increase YoY on Black Friday 2018- Nov 1, 2018, Market 373
 Highest Usage of COWM on Market for week 43-Nov 1, 2018
 2nd on Sales on Region on Black Friday 2018
 Top lottery sales in WM Supercenters in AZ- September 1, 2018